Eric D. Torres

New Orleans, LA 70116

Cell Phone: 504-722-0278 * E-mail: etorresnotary@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://etorres-revature.github.io/Responsive Portfolio/portfolio.html

GitHub: https://github.com/etorres-revature/

Summary

17+ years of successful business experience. Post-graduate law & executive business degrees, combined with an analytical mindset and uncompromising work ethic with complex problem solving, relationship development, and people management. Made a career shift to become a technical professional through a paid program with Revature for training and industry immersion to gain technical experience, object-oriented programming education and certifications for PEGA development. Ready to deploy technical skills in HTML5, CSS, and JavaScript as a full-stack web developer.

PROJECTS

Docket Master |

https://github.com/etorres-revature/Docket_Master | https://pure-atoll-36836.herokuapp.com/

Full-stack web-application designed for the maintenance and management of a fictional court system. Tracks cases, attorneys, litigants, case amounts, and case types. Authentication required to use web-app.

Responsible for design of back-end; implementation of routes; front-end layout; site hierarchy

Technologies: HTML5; CSS; Bootstrap 4; Node.js; Express.js; MySQL; Sequelize; AJAX; Twilio; Handlebars; jQuery

PORTFOLIO EDGE |

https://github.com/etorres-revature/Lucky Mountaineers | https://etorres-revature.github.io/Lucky Mountaineers/

Web app designed to provide up-to-the minute information about stocks. Information provided includes: Company Description, chart of previous twelve months prices, current quote information, and long-term price information.

Responsible for the front-end design, back-end development, and data integration.

<u>Technologies</u>: HTML5, CSS, Tailwind CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, server-side APIs, Chart.js.

Weather Dashboard |

https://github.com/etorres-revature/Weather Dashboard | https://etorres-revature.github.io/Weather Dashboard/

Web app that provides current and five-day weather information for any location around the world. Popular cities are provided, as well as local storage of previously searched cities.

Responsible for front-end, back-end, data integration, local storage.

<u>Technologies</u>: HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap 4, JavaScript, AJAX, server-side APIs, Moment.js.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Low-Code/No-Code: PEGA Platform

Languages: HTML5; CSS, JavaScript

Databases: SQL; MongoDB; MySQL

Frameworks/libraries: Chart.js; Moment.js; Node.js; Express.js; dotenv; Twilio; Handlebars;

Development Tools: GitHub; Git Bash; client-side APIs; server-side APIs

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer | 2020

Revature

- Intensive, three-month training bootcamp with exposure to principles of object-oriented programming, Java, SQL, CSS, HTML, AWS, and PEGA platform.
- Developed three projects 1 full-stack Java and 2 PEGA platform.

Associate Attorney | 2017-2019

ROBERT J. ELLIS LAW FIRM, LLC; New Orleans, LA

- Worked as associate for a solo practice focusing on municipal and state government solutions in general litigation, planning and zoning, and regulatory compliance matters.
- Conduct research and writing for legal memoranda and appellate briefs. Prepare, review, and file motions and petitions. Meet with agency staff, opposing counsel, clients, and other parties and stakeholders.
- Client portfolio includes developers, commercial and residential property owners, medical institutions, universities, area businesses, and state and local agencies.

Interim Executive Director | 2017

LOUISIANA STATE BOARD OF MEDICAL EXAMINERS; New Orleans, LA

- Served as Interim Executive Director during search process for an M.D. to permanently fill the role. Directed a staff of 40 with accountability for licensing 31,000 physicians and 13 other classifications of allied health professionals.
- Implemented a \$7.8 million budget, represented the Board at the Louisiana Legislature, worked with stakeholders on issues of policy, including medical marijuana, meaningful oversight, opioid abuse, and Health Professional Shortage Areas (HPSAs).

Business Operations Director / Health Promotion Unit | 2014-2016

LOUISIANA DEPT. OF HEALTH & HOSPITALS; Baton Rouge, LA

- Competitively selected as BOD of the Health Promotion Unit in the Office of Public Health in executing deliverables through facilitation of CDC grants. Managed Health Promotion Budget of ~\$5 million dollars in Cooperative Agreements.
- Drafted, routed, edited, and monitored contracts for payment and performance. Coordinated HR, Planning & Evaluation Sessions, Onboarding, and Policies & Procedures. Initiated Governor's state-wide Well-Ahead Louisiana campaign.

Program Support Coordinator / Assistant to the Undersecretary | 2012-2014

LOUISIANA DEPT. OF HEALTH & HOSPITALS; Baton Rouge, LA

- As Program Support Coordinator (2013-2014), worked within the Program Support & Waiver Unit of the Louisiana Medical Assistance Program (Medicaid), handling two multi-million dollar rebalancing programs.
- Coordinated with the Centers for Medicare & Medicaid Services and across agencies at DHH. Managed administrative, non-programmatic aspects of Operational Protocol, Annual Budget, and Quarterly Services Reporting.
- As Assistant to the Undersecretary (2012-2013), assisted in developing and implementing \$1.2 billion public-private partnerships for LSU Health Sciences Center safety net hospitals.
- Coordinating with 9 Louisiana hospitals on utilization and supplemental Medicaid payments. Worked with DHH staff, partner hospital executives, outside counsel, LSUHSC administrative staff, and others to execute all aspects of CEAs.
- In Spring 2013, assigned to Program Integrity-Compliance Unit, overseeing investigations and codified sanctions. Processed Mandatory & Permissive Exclusions and made recommendations on disclosure of ownership for Provider Enrollment.
- In Q1 & Q2 2012, closed 20+ files resulting in \$1 million+ dollar return to the LA Medicaid Program. Assigned to a high-volume docket of administrative adjudications and investigations.
- Prepared motions and pleadings to file with the Division of Administrative Law. Crafted discovery, presented cases before the Administrative Law Judge, and represented the department at the 19th Judicial District Court & Federal District Courts.

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full-Stack Web Development | 2021 (anticipated)

PEGA Ceertifcatres

Certified System Architect; Certified Senior System Architect; Certified Business Architect; Certified Robotics Architect

Juris Doctor (JD) | Admitted to Practice, Louisiana Bar | 2010

LOYOLA UNIVERSITY COLLEGE OF LAW; New Orleans, LA

Major: Civil Law | Evening Division

Leadership: Honor Board Evening Division Representative

Bachelor of Arts (BA) | 2001

TULANE UNIVERSITY; New Orleans, LA

Major: Political Science